<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Game Of Thrones</string>
    <string name="action_search">Cerca</string>
    <string name="action_compose">Favorits</string>
    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>
    <string name="text_desat">Desat a favorits</string>

    <!-- Noms de les casas i els seus lemas -->
    <string name="casa_stark">Stark</string>
    <string name="lema_stark">Winter Is Coming</string>
    <string name="casa_lanni">Lannister</string>
    <string name="lema_lanni">Hear Me Roar</string>
    <string name="casa_bara">Baratheon</string>
    <string name="lema_bara">Ours Is The Fury</string>
    <string name="casa_tyrell">Tyrell</string>
    <string name="lema_tyrell">Growing Strong</string>
    <string name="casa_grey">Greyjoy</string>
    <string name="lema_grey">We Do Not Sow</string>
    <string name="casa_arryn">Arryn</string>
    <string name="lema_arryn">As High As Honor</string>
    <string name="casa_bolton">Bolton</string>
    <string name="lema_bolton">Our Blades Are Sharp</string>

    <!-- Personatges de les casa Stark amb la seva descripció-->
    <string-array name="desc_stark">
        <item>
            \"The man who passes the sentence should swing the sword.\"\n
            -Eddard Stark\n\n
            Eddard is the head of House Stark and Lord Paramount of the North. The North is one of the
            constituent regions of the Seven Kingdoms, and House Stark is one of the Great House of
            the realm. House Stark rules the region from their seat of Winterfell, and Eddard also
            holds the little Lord of Winterfell. In addition, he is the Warden of the North.\n\n
            Eddard is married to Lady Catelyn of House Tully. Though they barely knew one another when
            they wed, they formed a strong and loving marriage. They have five legitimate children: Robb,
            Sansa, Arya, Bran and Rickon. Eddard also has an illegitimate bastard son, Jon Snow, reportedly
            by a common serving girl named Wylla. Jon\'s presence at Winterfell is a source of friction
            between Eddard and his wife. Nevertheless, Eddard was close to all his children and was
            well-loved an respected by all of them. He seemed to have a soft spot for his youngest daughter, Arya.\n\n
            Eddard is the second son of the Lord Rickard Stark. Lord Rickard served King Aerys II Targaryen
            as Warden of the North. Eddard\'s older brother Brandon was Rickard\'s heir. Eddard also
            has a younger sister Lyanna and a younger brother Benjen. Eddard is a stoic, dutiful, and
            honorable man and is considered to embody the values of the north.\n\n
        </item>
        <item>
            \"Show them how it feels to lose what they love.\"\n
            -Catelyn Stark\n\n
            Catelyn is from House Tully and married into House Stark. She is a devoted mother and is
        fiercely protective of her children. Her husband, Eddard Stark, is the Lord paramount of the
        North. He becomes Hand of the King to Robert Baratheon and travels south to the capital.
        Following an assassination attempt on her son Bran, she follows Eddard to warn him that
        House Lannister were involved. On her return journey she chances upon Tyrion Lannister and
        takes him into custody. This incites further conflict between the houses and Eddard is
        arrested for treason when Cersei Lannister becomes queen regent following the unexpected
        death of Robert. Catelyn is forced to release Tyrion when he proves his innocence in a trial
        by combat. She joins her son, Robb Stark, who has gathered the Stark banners to fight for
        Eddard\'s freedom. Eddard is executed on the order of King Joffrey Baratheon and Catelyn
        promises Robb that they will avenge him. While at the wedding of her brother to Roslin Frey,
        Catelyn is killed along with her son, his wife, and most of the Stark bannermen.\n\n
        </item>
        <item>
            \"I\'ve won every battle. But I\'m losing this war.\"\n
            -Robb Stark\n\n
            King Robb Stark is a major character in the first, second, and third seasons. He is
            played by starring cast member Richard Madden, and debuts in the series premiere. Robb
            is the eldest son of Lord Eddard Stark of Winterfell and his wife Lady Catelyn, brother
            of Sansa, Arya, Bran and Rickon Stark, and half-brother of Jon Snow, and adopts a direwolf
            named Grey Wind.\n\n
            Robb is the eldest child of Lady Catelyn and Lord Eddard Stark. Eddard is the head of
            House Stark, Lord of Winterfell and Lord Paramount of the North, one of the constituent
            regions of the Seven Kingdoms. The Starks rule the region from their seat of Winterfell.
            Eddard is also the Warden of the North to King Robert Baratheon\n\n
            Robb was born at Riverrun and raised in Winterfell. His father left his mother the morning
            after their wedding to fight in Robert\'s Rebellion and did not return until after Robb was
            born. He has two younger trueborn brothers, Bran and Rickon, and two sisters, Sansa and
            Arya. He is also close to his bastard half-brother, Jon Snow, and to his father\'s ward,
            Theon Greyjoy, whom he counts as his best friend outside of the family. He has been
            trained from childhood to wield a sword and wear armor by Winterfell\'s Master-at-Arms
            Ser Rodrik Cassel, and is highly proficient with both for his young age. He lives at
            Winterfell with his family.\n\n

        </item>
        <item>
            \"I\'m Sansa Stark of Winterfell. This is my home and you can\'t frighten me.\"\n
            -Sansa Stark to Myranda\n\n
            Sansa Stark is the eldest daughter and second child of Lady Catelyn and Lord Eddard Stark.
            Eddard is the head of House Stark and Lord Paramount of the North. The North is one of
            the constituent regions of the Seven Kingdoms and House Stark is one of the Great Houses
            of the realm. House Stark rules the region from their seat of Winterfell and Eddard also
            holds the titles of Lord of Winterfell and the Warden of the North to King Robert Baratheon.\n\n
            Sansa wa born and raised at Winterfell. She has an older brother, Robb, two younger brothers, Bran and
            Rickon, a younger sister, Arya and a bastard half-brother, Jon Snow. Sansa enjoys proper
            \"lady-like\" pursuits, and is good at sewing, embroidering, poetry, singing, literature and
            music. She dreams of being a regal Queen like Cersei Lannister, and that just like in the
            epic songs she will meet her knight in shining armor. She has inherited her mother\'s Tully
            coloring, unlike most of her siblings, and Lady Catelyn thinks Sansa will be even more
            beautiful than she was when she was younger. She is often seen in contrast with her sister,
            Arya Stark who has neither her looks nor her accomplishments in feminine activities and
            comportment.\n\n
        </item>
        <item>
            \"You know who I am. I\'m Arya Stark. Do you know who you are? You\'re no one. You\'re nothing.\"\n
            -Arya Stark to Meryn Trant\n\n
            Arya Stark is a major character in the first, second, third, fourth, fifth and sixth seasons.
        She is played by starring cast member Maisie Williams, and debuts in the series premiere.
        Arya is the younger daughter of Lord Eddard Stark and his wife Lady Catelyn Stark. She is
        headstrong, fiercely independent, disdains traditional women\'s pursuits, and thus is often
        mistaken for a boy. She wields a sword named Needle, a gift from her half-brother, Jon Snow,
        and was trained in the Braavosi style of swordfighting while living in King\'s Landing. She
        adopted the direwolf Nymeria, but they have since been separated after Nymeria attacked
        Joffrey, forcing Arya to send her away in order to prevent her execution.\n\n
            When her father is betrayed and executed by Joffrey, Arya flees the capital with the help
            of the Night\'s Watch recruiter, Yoren, who gets her out of the city disguised as an orphan
            boy \"Arry\" and tries to take her to Winterfell. On the way, she compiles a list of people
            she intends to kill. However, she is taken prisoner by Ser Gregor Clegane\'s men and taken
            to Harrenhal, where she briefly serves as cupbearer to an unsuspecting Tywin Lannister.
            After escaping, she begins making her way towards Riverrun and is captured by the Brotherhood
            Without Banners and subsequently by Sandor Clegane. They travel across Westeros as he
            unsuccessfully attempts to ransom her to various family members. In Clegane\'s company,
            Arya becomes increasingly hardened and brutalized, and personally kills a number of men.
            After Clegane is gravely injured in a fight, she abandons him. Long presumed dead by
            many in Westeros and with nowhere else to turn, Arya is now in Braavos, training with
            the Faceless Men. However, as a consequence of violating the assassins\' code, Arya has
            been rendered blind by the guild as punishment.\n\n
        </item>
        <item>
            \"My dreams are different.\"\n
            -Bran\n\n
            Brandon Stark, commonly called Bran, is a major character in the first, second, third,
        fourth and sixth seasons. He is played by starring cast member Isaac Hempstead-Wright and
        debuts in the series premiere. Bran Stark is a noble boy living with his family in Winterfell.
        He lost the use of his legs after being pushed out of a tower window by Jaime Lannister
        after discovering his incestuous relationship with Cersei Lannister. He relies on the servant
        Hodor to aid his mobility. He has had prophetic dreams.\n\n
            Bran adopted the direwolf Summer and they have forged a strong connection. He is able to
            see through the direwolf\'s eyes while he sleeps, as Bran is a Warg: a person who possesses
            the magical ability to enter the minds of animals and people. Bran is also blessed with the
            magical power of the Sight, which allows him to glimpse the past, elsewhere in the present
            and the future as well, often in dreams.\n\n
            Bran is the fourth child and second son of Lady Catelyn and Lord Eddard Stark. Eddard is
            the head of House Stark and Lord Paramount of the North. The North is one of the constituent
            regions of the Seven Kingdoms and House Stark is one of the Great Houses of the realm.
            House Stark rules the region from their seat of Winterfell and Eddard also holds the title
            Lord of Winterfell. He is also the Warden of the North to King Robert Baratheon.\n\n
        </item>
        <item>
            \"Robb\'s at war and I\'m going beyond the Wall. If something happens to us, you\'re the heir to W
            interfell.\"\n
            -Bran Stark when he sends Rickon away into hiding.\n\n
        Rickon Stark is a recurring character in the first, second, third and sixth seasons.
        He is played by guest star Art Parkinson and debuts in the series premiere.\n\n

        Rickon is the youngest son of Eddard Stark and Catelyn Stark and lives with his family in
        Winterfell until the Fall of Winterfell. Rickon adopted the direwolf Shaggydog and they have
        forged a strong connection. He traveled to find safety at Last Hearth with the wildling Osha
        after being separated from Hodor, Meera and Jojen Reed, and his brother Bran. His current
        whereabouts are unknown.\n\n
            Rickon is the fifth child and youngest son of Lady Catelyn and Lord Eddard Stark. Eddard
            is the head of House Stark and Lord Paramount of the North. The North is one of the
            constituent regions of the Seven Kingdoms and House Stark is one of the Great Houses
            of the realm. House Stark rule the region from their seat of Winterfell and Eddard also
            holds the title Lord of Winterfell. He is also the Warden of the North to King Robert Baratheon.\n\n
            Rickon was born and raised at Winterfell. He has two older brothers Robb and Bran and two
            older sisters Sansa and Arya. He also has an older bastard half-brother of Jon Snow. He
            is six years old when his uncle and Hand of the King, Lord Jon Arryn, dies.\n\n
        </item>
        <item><string>
           \"I\'m not asking you to forget your dead. I\'ll never forget mine. I lost fifty brothers
            the night that Mance attacked the Wall. But I\'m asking you to think about your children now.
            They\'ll never have children of their own if we don\'t band together. The Long Night is coming
            and the dead come with it. No clan can stop them. The Free Folk can\'t stop them, the Night\'s
            Watch can\'t stop them and all the southern kings can\'t stop them! Only together. All of us.
            And even then it may not be enough, but at least we give the fuckers a fight.\"\n -Jon Snow\n\n
            Jon is the bastard son of Lord Eddard Stark of Winterfell, the head of House Stark and Lord
            Paramount of the North. The North is one of the constituent regions of the Seven Kingdoms in
            Westeros, and House Stark is one of the Great Houses of the realm. House Stark rules the
            region from their seat of Winterfell and Eddard also holds the title Lord of Winterfell.
            He is also the Warden of the North to King Robert Baratheon.\n\n Eddard once told King
            Robert Baratheon that Jon\'s mother is a serving girl named Wylla, but refused to elaborate
            any further. Jon himself has no knowledge of his mother, not knowing if she\'s alive or not.\n\n
            Jon was raised at Winterfell on an equal footing with Eddard\'s legitimate children. He
            has an older half-brother Robb, two younger half-sisters Sansa and Arya, and two younger
            half-brothers Bran and Rickon. Jon\'s presence at Winterfell is a source of friction between
            Eddard and his wife, Catelyn, although Catelyn put aside her anger temporarily when the infant
            Jon became severely ill. Jon got on well with his half-siblings, particularly Robb and Arya.\n\n
        </string></item>
    </string-array>

    <!-- Personatges de la casa Lannister amb la seva descripció-->
    <string-array name="desc_lannister">
        <item>
            \"Before long I\'ll be dead, and you and your brother and your sister and all of her
            children, all of us dead, all of us rotting in the ground. It\'s the family name that lives
            on. It\'s all that lives on. Not your personal glory, not your honor. but family.\"\n
            -Lord Tywin Lannister to Ser Jaime Lannister.\n\n
            Tywin is the lord of House Lannister, the Lord Paramount of the Westerlands, and the
            richest man in the Seven Kingdoms. The Westerlands are one of the constituent regions of
            the Seven Kingdoms and House Lannister is one of the Great Houses of the realm. House
            Lannister rule the region from their seat of Casterly Rock and Tywin also holds the title
            Lord of Casterly Rock. He is also the Warden of the West. He is a widower with three
            children, Jaime, Cersei and Tyrion. Casterly Rock, the Lannister\'s ancestral seat
            of power, is located over a group of highly productive goldmines, which have provided the
            Lannisters with immense wealth over the years and led to the speculation that Tywin \"shits gold.\"\n\n
            Tywin is the son of Tytos Lannister. His father presided over a period of decline for the
            house, frittering away much of their fortune on poor investments and allowing himself to
            be mocked at court, creating a perception of weakness. Their vassals House Reyne of
            Castamere rebelled against Lord Tytos, and Tywin put down the rebellion personally,
            extinguishing their house and re-establishing the fearsome reputation of House Lannister.
            His ruthless destruction of House Reyne was immortalized in the song \"The Rains of Castamere\"
            and gave darker meaning to the common phrase \"A Lannister always pays his debts,\" which
            originally referred solely to the Lannister\'s vast fortune.\n\n
        </item>
        <item>
            \"You\'ve always been funny, but none of your jokes will ever match the first one, will
            they? You remember, back when you ripped my mother open on your way out of her, and she
            bled to death.\"\n
            -Cersei Lannister to Tyrion Lannister.\n\n
            Joanna was the wife of Tywin Lannister, the head of House Lannister and the Lord of Casterly
            Rock. Joanna was perhaps the only person Tywin loved unconditionally. Joanna bore him the
            twins Jaime and Cersei. She died giving birth to Tyrion. Joanna died when Cersei and
            Jaime were only four years old. Tywin took Joanna\'s death very hard, as did Cersei, who
            holds Tyrion responsible for her death. However, Jaime understands that Tyrion was
            just an infant and had no control over what happened.\n\n
        </item>
        <item>
            \"There are no men like me, only me.\"\n
            -Jaime Lannister\n\n
            Ser Jaime Lannister is a knight of the Kingsguard, a position he has held for twenty years
            since he was a teenager, the youngest man ever appointed to its membership. He was
            appointed to the position by the Mad King, Aerys II Targaryen.\n\n
            At the conclusion of Robert\'s Rebellion, Jaime\'s father Tywin betrayed King Aerys by
            arriving at the gates of King\'s Landing with the main Lannister army and pleading his
            allegiance, then after his army was allowed inside the gates, turning them loose to attack
            the city. As Lannister soldiers raped and pillaged throughout the city during the Sack of
            King\'s Landing, King Aerys remained holed up inside the Red Keep, for hours maniacally
            repeating the order to \"burn them all\". Despite being sworn by the holiest oaths to protect
            the king as a member of the Kingsguard, Jaime ultimately turned his own sword on Aerys,
            slaying him at the foot of the Iron Throne itself. For this infamous act, he is known
            throughout the Seven Kingdoms as the \"Kingslayer\", to his irritation.\n\n
        </item>
        <item>
            \"I will do things for my family you couldn\'t imagine. I love my brother, I love my lover.
            People will whisper, they\'ll make their jokes - let them. They\'re all so small
            I can\'t even see them.\"\n
            -Cersei to Jaime Lannister\n\n
            Cersei is the only daughter and eldest child of Joanna Lannister and Lord Tywin Lannister.
            Tywin is the head of House Lannister, the richest man in the Seven Kingdoms and Lord
            Paramount of the Westerlands. The Westerlands are one of the constituent regions of the
            Seven Kingdoms and House Lannister is one of the Great Houses of the realm. Cersei is the
            elder twin of Ser Jaime Lannister and the elder sister of Tyrion Lannister. She was raised
            in privilege in the family seat of Casterly Rock. She is noted for her great beauty.\n\n
            Cersei\'s mother died when she was four years old, after giving birth to her younger brother
            Tyrion. Like her father, Cersei has always blamed Tyrion for her mother\'s death and deeply
            resents that her mother died so that Tyrion would be brought into the world. Cersei\'s father
            Tywin was constantly away from home during her childhood and teenaged years, serving as
            Hand of the King at the capital, with only infrequent visits back to his seat at Casterly
            Rock. Coupled with the death of her mother, this meant that Cersei and her two brothers
            were primarily raised by servants attached to House Lannister. She began an incestuous
            relationship with Jaime in her youth which has continued despite her marriage. Cersei
            has had other partners but Jaime has always been faithful to her.\n\n
        </item>
        <item>
            Tyrion Lannister: \"I\'m guilty of a far more monstrous crime: I\'m guilty of being a dwarf!\"\n
            Tywin Lannister: \"You are not on trial for being a dwarf.\"\n
            Tyrion Lannister: \"Oh, yes I am! I\'ve been on trial for that my entire life!\"\n
            -Tyrion at his trial, falsely accused of killing his nephew King Joffrey\n\n
            Tyrion Lannister is the youngest son of Joanna Lannister and Lord Tywin Lannister. Tywin
            is the head of House Lannister, the richest man in the Seven Kingdoms and Lord Paramount
            of the Westerlands. The Westerlands are one of the constituent regions of the Seven Kingdoms
            and House Lannister of Casterly Rock is one of the Great Houses of the realm. He is the
            younger brother of Jaime and Cersei Lannister. His mother Joanna Lannister died giving
            birth to him. His father and sister hold him in contempt as they blame him for the death.\n\n
            He is a dwarf, causing him problems and persecution. His size has led him to being referred
            to derisively by various names, such as \"the Imp\" and \"The Halfman\". This is mitigated by
            his intellect and his family\'s wealth and power. Had an infant with dwarfism like Tyrion
            been born a commoner, he\'d have simply been left out in the woods to die. However, Tyrion
            was born into a powerful noble House, and was therefore spared. Even though his father
            doesn\'t think much of him, he has had the benefits of being raised with wealth and education,
            and is expected to lead his life as a credit to the Lannister name. He is committed to
            the good of both his House and, since Cersei married King Robert Baratheon, his family\'s
            continued hold on the throne.\n\n
        </item>
    </string-array>

    <!-- Personatges de la casa Baratheon amb la seva descripció-->
    <string-array name="desc_baratheon">
        <item>
            \"I\'m not trying to honor you. I\'m trying to get you to rum my kingdom while I eat, drink,
            and whore my way to an early grave.\"\n
            -Robert Baratheon to Eddard Stark\n\n
            Robert Baratheon was the ruler of the Seven Kingdoms, formally styled as Robert of the House
            Baratheon, the Firts of His Name, King of the Andals and the Firts Men, Lord of the Seven
            Kingdoms and Protector of the Realm. He tooks the throne through conquest in the war known
            as Robert\'s Rebellion. Robert was a great warrior in his youth. He killed Rhaegar Targaryen,
            Prince of Dragonstone, at the Battle of the Trident. After the war, Robert married Cersei
            Lannister to cement an alliance with House Lannister was loveless. Robert and Cersei have
            three children: Joffrey, Myrcella and Tommen. Unbeknnown to Robert, all three were actually
            fathered by Cersei\'s twin brother, Jaime Lannister.\n\n
        </item>
        <item>
            \"I will do things for my family you couldn\'t imagine. I love my brother, I love my lover.
            People will whisper, they\'ll make their jokes - let them. They\'re all so small
            I can\'t even see them.\"\n
            -Cersei to Jaime Lannister\n\n
            Cersei is the only daughter and eldest child of Joanna Lannister and Lord Tywin Lannister.
            Tywin is the head of House Lannister, the richest man in the Seven Kingdoms and Lord
            Paramount of the Westerlands. The Westerlands are one of the constituent regions of the
            Seven Kingdoms and House Lannister is one of the Great Houses of the realm. Cersei is the
            elder twin of Ser Jaime Lannister and the elder sister of Tyrion Lannister. She was raised
            in privilege in the family seat of Casterly Rock. She is noted for her great beauty.\n\n
            Cersei\'s mother died when she was four years old, after giving birth to her younger brother
            Tyrion. Like her father, Cersei has always blamed Tyrion for her mother\'s death and deeply
            resents that her mother died so that Tyrion would be brought into the world. Cersei\'s father
            Tywin was constantly away from home during her childhood and teenaged years, serving as
            Hand of the King at the capital, with only infrequent visits back to his seat at Casterly
            Rock. Coupled with the death of her mother, this meant that Cersei and her two brothers
            were primarily raised by servants attached to House Lannister. She began an incestuous
            relationship with Jaime in her youth which has continued despite her marriage. Cersei
            has had other partners but Jaime has always been faithful to her.\n\n
        </item>
        <item>
            \"We\'ve had vicious kings, and we\'ve had idiot kings, but I don\'t know if we\'ve ever
            been cursed with a vicious idiot for a king!\"\n
            -Tyrion Lannister, summarizing his nephew Joffrey Baratheon.\n\n
            Joffrey is believed to be the oldest son and their of King Robert Baratheon and Queen Cersei
            Lannister, both of whom entered into a political marriage alliance afther Robert took the
            throne by force from the Mad King Aerys II Targaryen. In reality, his father is Jaime Lannister,
            the queen\'s brother and the Lord Commander of the Kingsguard. He has a younger sister,
            Myrcella, and a younger brother, Tommen, both whom are also the product of Jaime and Cersei\'s
            incest. Their sole biological grandparents, Twin and Joanna Lannister, were also apparently
            firts cousins.\n\n
        </item>
        <item>
            \"I know. Abaout you and mother. I think a part of me always knew. And I\'m glad. I\'m glad
            that you\'re my father.\"\n
            -Myrcella Baratheon to her \"uncle\" Jaime Lannister.\n\n
            Princess Myrcella Baratheon is a recurring character in seassons. She is portrayed by guest
            star Nell Tiger Free, taking over the role (starting in Season 5) from Aimee Richardson,
            who played the character in Seasons 1 and 2 and debuts in the series premiere. Princess
            Myrcella is commonly thought Robert Baratheon and Queen Cersei Lannister. However, like
            her siblings, her real father is Jaime Lannister. Her younger brother Tommen Baratheon
            currently sits on the Iron Throne as the King of the Andals and the First Men. She was sent
            to Dorne as part of a marriage pact with House Martell, and although she was allowed to
            return to King\'s Landing with her betrothed by Doran Martell, she was poisoned and murdered
            by Ellaria Sand and the Sand Snakes as revenge against Cersei for the death of Oberyn
            Martell.\n\n
        </item>
        <item>
            \"My father, maybe Joffrey was too much work for him. Sweet Tommen will be so much
            easier to handle.\"\n
            -Tyrion Lannister\n\n
            King Tommen Baratheon is a major character in the fifth and sixth seasons. He initially
        appeared as a recurring character in the first, second and fourth seasons. He is portrayed
        by starring cast member Dean-Charles Chapman, taking over the role (starting in Season 4)
        from Callum Wharry, who played the character briefly in Seasons 1 and 2. Tommen is the younger
        brother of late King Joffrey and Princess Myrcella, and Joffrey\'s heir presumptive to the
        Iron Throne. Though legally the son of the late King Robert Baratheon and Queen Cersei Lannister,
        his true father is Ser Jaime Lannister, the Queen\'s twin brother. His sole biological
        grandparents, Tywin and Joanna Lannister, were also first cousins.\n\n
        </item>
        <item>
            \"No act done in the service of the Lord of Light can ever be a sin.\"\n
            -Selyse Baratheon\n\n
            Selyse is the wife of Stannis Baratheon, the Lord of Dragonstone and claimant to the Iron
            Throne. She was born into House Florent of Brightwater Keep, a noble house of the Reach
            and bannermen of House Tyrell.\n\n
            Selyse and Stannis have a single daughter, Princess Shireen Baratheon. The rest of Selyse
            and Stannis\' offspring, Petyr, Tommard, and Edric, were all stillborn. She keeps their
            bodies in crystal containers filled with chemicals in her chambers.\n\n
        </item>
    </string-array>

    <!-- Personatges de les casa Tyrell amb la seva descripció-->
    <string-array name="desc_tyrell">
        <item>
            \"Not now, Mace, Lord Tywin and I are speaking!\"\n
            -Lord Mace Tyrell is chided by his mother, Olenna\n\n

            Mace Tyrell is a recurring character in the fourth, fifth and sixth seasons. He is
            played by guest star Roger Ashton-Griffiths and debuts in \"The Lion and the Rose\".\n\n

            Lord Mace Tyrell is the Lord of Highgarden and head of House Tyrell. He is the father of
            Loras and Margaery Tyrell, and the son of Olenna Tyrell. He initially supported Renly
            Baratheon\'s claim to the Iron Throne in the War of the Five Kings, but after Renly\'s
            death he successfully negotiated an alliance with House Lannister to support King
            Joffrey\'s claim to the throne, on the condition that his daughter Margaery would marry
            Joffrey, making her the new queen and giving House Tyrell the prestige of entering into
            the royal bloodline. He has since been appointed both Master of Ships and Master of Coin
            on the Small Council.\n\n
        </item>
        <item>
            Alerie Hightower is the daughter of Lord Leyton Hightower, Lord of Oldtown, and the
            spouse of Lord Mace Tyrell of Highgarden. She is the mother of his four children, Willas,
            Garlan, Loras and Margaery.\n\n
        </item>
        <item>
            Willas Tyrell is a character cut from Game of Thrones. He has only appeared in the House
            Tyrell family tree issued by HBO. He is the eldest son of Mace Tyrell, the Lord of Highgarden.\n\n

            Willas Tyrell is the eldest son of Mace Tyrell and Alerie Tyrell. He has two younger
            brothers Garlan and Loras and one sister Margaery.\n\n
        </item>
        <item>
            Garlan Tyrell is the second son of Mace Tyrell and Alerie Tyrell. Mace is the Lord of
            Highgarden and head of House Tyrell. He has two brothers Willas and Loras and one sister
            Margaery.\n
        </item>
        <item>
            \"Where is it written that power is the sole province of the worst? That thrones are only
            made for the hated and the feared? You would be a wonderful king.\"\n
            -Loras Tyrell to Renly Baratheon\n\n

            Ser Loras Tyrell is a recurring character in the first, second, third, fourth, fifth and
            sixth seasons. He is played by guest star Finn Jones and debuts in \"The Wolf and the Lion.\"
            Ser Loras Tyrell, the heir to Highgarden, is a popular tourney knight and ranks as one of
            the most skilled knights in Westeros. He was the lover of Renly Baratheon and supported
            his claim to the Iron Throne as commander of his Kingsguard. After Renly is murdered,
            Loras correctly deduces his brother Stannis Baratheon is responsible and swears vengeance.
            He joins forces with King Joffrey and Tywin Lannister in the War of the Five Kings, and
            helps them defeat Stannis at the Battle of the Blackwater. Since then, however, he has
            been arrested by the re-established Faith Militant for his homosexuality, and is set to
            stand trial.\n\n
        </item>
        <item>
            Petyr Baelish: \"Do you want to be a queen?\"\n
            Margaery Tyrell: \"No. I want to be the Queen.\"\n
            -Margaery Tyrell to Littlefinger\n\n

            Queen Margaery Tyrell is a major character in the second, third, fourth, fifth, and sixth
            seasons. She is played by Natalie Dormer and debuts in \"What is Dead May Never Die.\"
            Margaery is the widow of King Renly Baratheon, a claimant to the Iron Throne in the War
            of the Five Kings. Her father Lord Mace Tyrell is the ruler of the Reach. She is betrothed
            to King Joffrey Baratheon after the Battle of Blackwater, and briefly becomes his queen,
            but this is cut short when Joffrey is fatally poisoned at their wedding feast. She
            subsequently was betrothed to Joffrey\'s younger brother and successor, Tommen Baratheon.
            Margaery is known for her beauty, political cunning, and ambition, although she has a
            compassionate side. Due to Cersei Lannister\'s machinations, Margaery has recently been
            arrested by the Faith Militant for perjury on her brother Loras\'s behalf, and the two
            are to stand trial.\n\n
        </item>
        <item>
            Olenna Tyrell: \"Loras is young and very good at knocking men off horses with a stick.
            That does not make him wise. As for your fathead father\"\n
            Margaery Tyrell: \"Grandmother! What will Sansa think of us?\"\n
            Olenna Tyrell: \"She might think we have some wits about us, one of us at any rate.\"\n
            -Margaery Tyrell introduces her grandmother Olenna to Sansa Stark\n\n

            Olenna Tyrell, née Redwyne, is a recurring character in the third, fourth, fifth and sixth
            seasons. She is played by Diana Rigg.\n\n

            The elderly matriarch of House Tyrell, Lady Olenna has been a master of court politics
            and intrigue par excellence throughout her life. She\'s also known for her wit and sarcasm.
            As a result, Lady Olenna is popularly nicknamed the Queen of Thorns, in reference to her
            House\'s sigil and her cutting barbs. In many ways she is the de facto head of House Tyrell
            at the time of the War of the Five Kings and appears to hold a great deal of influence
            over the Reach.\n\n
        </item>
        <item>
            Garth Tyrell, better known as Garth the Gross, is the uncle of Lord Mace Tyrell. He
            serves his nephew as the Lord Seneschal of Highgarden, as he served Mace\'s father Lord
            Luthor. He has two bastard sons, Garse and Garrett Flowers. He is flatulent.
        </item>
    </string-array>

    <!-- Personatges de les casa Greyjoy amb la seva descripció-->
    <string-array name="desc_greyjoy">
        <item>
            \"No man gives me a crown. I pay the iron price. I will take my crown.\"\n
            -Balon Greyjoy\n\n

            King Balon Greyjoy is a recurring character in the second, third and sixth seasons. He
            is played by guest star Patrick Malahide and debuts in \"The Night Lands.\" Balon Greyjoy
            is the Lord Reaper of Pyke and the head of House Greyjoy. He is the father of Yara and
            Theon Greyjoy.\n\n

            Balon Greyjoy is the head of House Greyjoy and Lord of the Iron Islands. The Iron Islands
            are one of the constituent regions of the Seven Kingdoms and House Greyjoy is one of the
            Great Houses of the realm. House Greyjoy rule the region from their seat at Pyke and Balon
            also holds the title Lord Reaper of Pyke. He is a hard, ambitious and ruthless man.\n\n

            Balon is married to Alannys of House Harlaw. They had four children Rodrik, Maron, Yara
            and Theon. Yara is their only daughter.\n\n

            Eight years before the start of the series Balon declared himself King of the Iron Islands
            and rose in the rebellion against the Iron Throne to revive the \"Old Way\", which had once
            led the ironborn to rule much of the western coast of Westeros. He was, however, defeated
            in a bloody war. His elder two sons were killed and his third son, Theon, was taken by Lord
            Eddard Stark as a hostage for Balon\'s good behavior and obedience. Yara has remained on
            the Iron Islands and has become a warrior and captain in her own right, which is unusual
            for women on the isles.\n\n
        </item>
        <item>
            \"They skinned our countrymen and they mutilated my brother, your prince. YOUR PRINCE!
            Everything they\'ve done to him, they\'ve also done to you! As long as they can hurt our
            prince with impunity, the word "ironborn" means nothing!\"\n
            -Yara Greyjoy\n\n
            Asha was fairly unattractive in her youth. Her uncle, Victarion Greyjoy, remembers Asha
            as a little girl swimming naked in the sea and playing with her doll. After Theon
            Greyjoy\'s departure for Winterfell to be Eddard Stark\'s hostage and ward, Asha became Lord
            Balon Greyjoy\'s only remaining child in Pyke. Her mother, Lady Alannys Harlaw, fostered
            five boys at Pyke after Theon\'s departure. Tristifer Botley, the boy closest to Asha in
            age, developed an infatuation with her when they went through puberty, but Asha did not
            reciprocate his affections.\n\n

            Asha grew into an attractive and bold young woman, and Balon effectively raised her as
            his heir. However, Asha preferred Ten Towers, the seat of her uncle Rodrik Harlaw, to
            Pyke. She lost her virtue at age 16 to a sailor from Lys. In 293 AC or 294 AC Asha
            sailed the Black Wind on a trading voyage which included stops at Fair Isle, Lannisport,
            and the Arbor, where she introduced peaches to one of her lovers, Qarl the Maid.\n\n
        </item>
        <item>
            \"Your name is Theon Greyjoy, last surviving son of Balon Greyjoy, Lord of the Iron Islands,
            do you hear me?\"\n
            ―Sansa Stark to Theon Greyjoy\n\n
            Theon is the youngest son of Lord Balon and Lady Alannys Greyjoy. Balon is the head of
            House Greyjoy and Lord of the Iron Islands. The Iron Islands are one of the constituent
            regions of the Seven Kingdoms and House Greyjoy is one of the Great Houses of the realm.
            House Greyjoy rule the region from their seat at Pyke and Balon also holds the title
            Lord Reaper of Pyke.\n\n
            Theon was born at Pyke. He is Balon and Alannys\' fourth child after Rodrik, Maron, and
            Yara. Eight years before the start of the series Balon rose in rebellion against the Iron
            Throne. The ironborn were crushed in a war led by King Robert Baratheon and Lord Eddard
            Stark. Theon\'s brothers were both killed in the fighting. Balon surrendered and was allowed
            to remain Lord of the Iron Islands on the condition that Theon remain a hostage and ward
            of Eddard Stark. Theon\'s sister Yara remained on the Iron Islands. Despite his
            status as a hostage at Winterfell, Theon was treated well by the Starks, and he came to
            see Eddard as a surrogate father, while becoming best friends with Robb Stark. Theon is
            a skilled archer. His cocky arrogance and cavalier actions contrast with the staid ways
            of the North.\n\n
        </item>
        <item>
            \"I still remember seeing my father\'s fleet burn in Lannisport. I believe your uncles were
            responsible.\"\n
            ―Tyrion Lannister to Theon Greyjoy in Season 1.\n\n
            Euron Greyjoy is a character set to appear in the sixth season, though he was previously
            mentioned indirectly in the Season 1 episode \"Cripples, Bastards and Broken Things\". He
            will be portrayed by Pilou Asbæk. He is the younger brother of King Balon Greyjoy, older
            brother of Aeron Greyjoy, and the eldest uncle of Theon and Yara Greyjoy.\n\n

            \"Euron\" is pronounced \"Your-on\", not \"You-ron\" or \"Yew-ron\".\n\n
        </item>
        <item>
            \"I still remember seeing my father\'s fleet burn in Lannisport. I believe your uncles were responsible.\"\n
            ―Tyrion Lannister to Theon Greyjoy\n\n
            Victarion Greyjoy is an unseen character in Game of Thrones. He has only appeared in the
            first season House Greyjoy family tree issued by HBO. He is an uncle of Theon Greyjoy.\n\n
            Victarion Greyjoy is the younger brother of Balon Greyjoy, Head of House Greyjoy and the
            Lord Reaper of Pyke. Victarion is the Lord Captain of the Iron Fleet. His other brothers
            are Euron Greyjoy and Aeron Greyjoy.\n\n
        </item>
        <item>
            Aeron Greyjoy is a character in the sixth season. His appearance in Season 6 is
            confirmed but the actor portraying him is not yet known.\n
            Aeron Greyjoy is the youngest brother of Balon Greyjoy, head of House Greyjoy and the
            Lord Reaper of Pyke. He is also the younger brother of Euron and an uncle of Yara and
            Theon Greyjoy. He is a Drowned Priest in service to the Drowned God.\n
        </item>
        <item>
            \"We both loved our mother. We both endured our father.\"\n
            ―Yara Greyjoy\n\n
            Alannys Greyjoy was born into House Harlaw and married Balon Greyjoy, head of House
            Greyjoy and the Lord Reaper of Pyke. They had four children: Rodrik, Maron, Yara, and
            Theon. Only her daughter Yara and her youngest son Theon are still alive.\n
            Her two eldest sons were killed in the Greyjoy Rebellion. Balon Greyjoy surrendered his
            and Alannys\' only surviving son Theon, then aged 10, as a hostage as punishment for the
            uprising and to ensure there would be no others. Eddard Stark volunteered to raise Theon
            as his ward in Winterfell.\n\n
        </item>
    </string-array>

    <!-- Personatges de la casa Arryn amb la seva descripció-->
    <string-array name="desc_arryn">
        <item>
            \"The seed is strong.\"\n
            Jon Arryn\'s last words\n\n
            Jon Arryn was the Lord of the Eyrie and the head of House Arryn, one of the Great Houses
            of Westeros. Jos was the Warden of the East and Defender of the Vale. He was a respected
            nobleman were fostered by him during their adolescence. The Mad King condoned the kidnap
            of Eddard\'a sister and Robert\'s betrothed Lyanna Stark. The Mad King Eddard\'s father
            and brother killed for protesting against the kidnapping. When he then demanded that Eddard
            and Robert be turned over to the King\'s justice, Lord Arryn rebelled, calling his banners
            to war. House Stark and House Baratheon followed suit. The rebels forged an alliance with
            House Tully through marriage, with Eddard married Catelyn Tully and the then-elderly Jon
            to the young Lysa Tully.\n\n
        </item>
        <item>
            \"Mummy, I want to see the bad man fly.\"\n
            -Robin Arryn\n\n
            Robin was born in King\'s Landing where his father was serving as the Hand of the King for
            Robert Baratheon. Jon begins an investigation into Rober\'s legitimate and bastard children
            and then takes a fever and dies suddenly. Robin inherits Jon\'s posisition. Lysa rushes
            Robin back to the Eyrie following Jon\'s death. She writes to her sister to accuse House
            Lannister of poisoning Jon. Lysa was fiercely proctective of Robin and he leads an extremely
            sheltered life.\n\n
        </item>
        <item>
            Harrold was born the eldest son of a landed knight of House Hardyng and the youngest
            daughter of Alys Arryn and Ser Elys Waynwood. He was taken in as Lady Anya Waynwood\'s
            ward at Ironoaks and was raised there. Harrold is still young but it is rumored that,
            despite his youth, he has already fathered a bastard daughter.\n\n
            Harrold later confirms during a tournament at the Gates of the Moon to join the
            Brotherhood of Winged Knights that he has a two year old bastard daughter named Alys,
            whom he fathered on a girl named Cissy. According to Harrold, childbirth left Cissy \"fat
            as a cow\", so Lady Waynwood arranged for her to be married off to one of her men-at-arms.
            Sometime afterwards, Harrold impregnated the daughter of one of the richest spice
            merchants in Gulltown named Saffron. She is expected to give birth to his second
            acknowledged bastard.\n\n
        </item>
    </string-array>

    <!--Personatges de la casa Bolton amb la seva descripció-->
    <string-array name="desc_bolton">
        <item>
            \"In my family we say, \'A naked man has few secrets, a flayed man, none.\'\"\n
            -Roose Bolton\n\n
            Roose Bolton is the head of House Bolton, a vassal family to House Stark of Winterfell.
            He is the Lord of the Dreadfort. Roose takes pride in his house sigil; the flayed man.
            Although torture is outlawed in the North, his family is famous for flaying the skin
            from their enemies as a means of torture and execution. Roose fought for Lord Eddard
            Stark in the civil war against House Targaryen known as Robert\'s Rebellion and proved
            his worth as a soldier in the Battle of the Trident. He advised Robert Baratheon to execute
            Ser Barristan Selmy, a legendary Kingsguard sworn to the Targaryens, but Robert overruled
            Roose and pardoned Selmy.\n\n
            Roose Bolton had a trueborn son, Domeric, who perished, forcing Roose to rely on his
            bastard son, Ramsay Snow.\n\n
        </item>
        <item>
            \"Lord Walder let me choose any of his granddaughters and promised me the girl\'s weight in
            silver as a dowry, so i have a fat young bride.\"\n
            -Roose Bolton\n\n
            Walda Bolton, née Frey, better know as Fat Walda, is a recurring character in the fourth,
            fifth and sixth seasons. She is the new wife of Roose Bolton, the Lord of the Dreadfort.
            She is portrayed by Elizabeth Webster.\n\n
        </item>
        <item>
            \"If you think this has a happy ending, you haven\'t been paying attention.\"\n
            -Ramsay Bolton to Theon Greyjoy\n\n
            Ramsay Snow, better know as \"The Bastard of Bolton\", is Lord Roose Bolton\'s bastard son
            and the product of rape: years ago Roose discovered that a miller had wed without his
            permission. He had the miller hanged and raped his wife. Ramsay was born shortly afterwards,
            and his mother brought him to the Dreadfort, his father\'s castle, for Roose to acknowledge as
            his son. Roose very nearly killed both Ramsay and his mother, but relented upon realizing that
            the child was indeed his.\n\n
            Ramsay is Roose\'s only living child following the death of Domeric Bolton, as well as the
            only possible heir to House Bolton until the birth of a child by Roose\'s new wife, Fat Walda
            Frey. He Stayed Behind as castellan of the Dreadfort when his father left for the south
            to fight in the War of the Five Kings.\n\n
        </item>
    </string-array>


    <!-- Llista personatges de la casa Stark-->
    <string-array name="personatges_starks">
        <item>Eddard Stark</item>
        <item>Catelyn Tully</item>
        <item>Robb Stark</item>
        <item>Sansa Stark</item>
        <item>Arya Stark</item>
        <item>Brandon Stark</item>
        <item>Rickon Stark</item>
        <item>Jon Snow</item>
    </string-array>

    <string name="eddardname">Eddard Stark</string>
    <string name="eddard_desc">Lord of Winterfell, 35 years.</string>
    <string name="eddard_desc_large">\"The man who passes the sentence should swing the sword.\"\n
            -Eddard Stark\n\n
            Eddard is the head of House Stark and Lord Paramount of the North. The North is one of the
            constituent regions of the Seven Kingdoms, and House Stark is one of the Great House of
            the realm. House Stark rules the region from their seat of Winterfell, and Eddard also
            holds the little Lord of Winterfell. In addition, he is the Warden of the North.\n\n
            Eddard is married to Lady Catelyn of House Tully. Though they barely knew one another when
            they wed, they formed a strong and loving marriage. They have five legitimate children: Robb,
            Sansa, Arya, Bran and Rickon. Eddard also has an illegitimate bastard son, Jon Snow, reportedly
            by a common serving girl named Wylla. Jon\'s presence at Winterfell is a source of friction
            between Eddard and his wife. Nevertheless, Eddard was close to all his children and was
            well-loved an respected by all of them. He seemed to have a soft spot for his youngest daughter, Arya.\n\n
            Eddard is the second son of the Lord Rickard Stark. Lord Rickard served King Aerys II Targaryen
            as Warden of the North. Eddard\'s older brother Brandon was Rickard\'s heir. Eddard also
            has a younger sister Lyanna and a younger brother Benjen. Eddard is a stoic, dutiful, and
            honorable man and is considered to embody the values of the north.\n\n</string>

    <!-- Array amb les descripcions curtes de la casa Stark-->
    <string-array name="per_starks_descr">
        <item></item>
        <item>Lady of Winterfell, 35 years.</item>
        <item>King in the North, 16 years.</item>
        <item>Princess of Winterfell, 14 years.</item>
        <item>Princess of Winterfell, 11 years.</item>
        <item>Prince of Winterfell, 10 years.</item>
        <item>Prince of Winterfell, 5 years.</item>
        <item>Lord Commander of the Night\'s Watch, 17 years.</item>
    </string-array>


    <!-- Llista personatges de la casa Lannister-->
    <string-array name="personatges_lann">
        <item>Tywin Lannister</item>
        <item>Joanna Lannister</item>
        <item>Jaime Lannister</item>
        <item>Cersei Lannister</item>
        <item>Tyrion Lannister</item>
    </string-array>

    <string name="tywim_name">Tywin Lannister</string>
    <string name="tywin_desc">Lord of Casterly Rock, 58 years.</string>
    <string name="tywin_desc_large">\"Before long I\'ll be dead, and you and your brother and your sister and all of her
            children, all of us dead, all of us rotting in the ground. It\'s the family name that lives
            on. It\'s all that lives on. Not your personal glory, not your honor. but family.\"\n
            -Lord Tywin Lannister to Ser Jaime Lannister.\n\n
            Tywin is the lord of House Lannister, the Lord Paramount of the Westerlands, and the
            richest man in the Seven Kingdoms. The Westerlands are one of the constituent regions of
            the Seven Kingdoms and House Lannister is one of the Great Houses of the realm. House
            Lannister rule the region from their seat of Casterly Rock and Tywin also holds the title
            Lord of Casterly Rock. He is also the Warden of the West. He is a widower with three
            children, Jaime, Cersei and Tyrion. Casterly Rock, the Lannister\'s ancestral seat
            of power, is located over a group of highly productive goldmines, which have provided the
            Lannisters with immense wealth over the years and led to the speculation that Tywin \"shits gold.\"\n\n
            Tywin is the son of Tytos Lannister. His father presided over a period of decline for the
            house, frittering away much of their fortune on poor investments and allowing himself to
            be mocked at court, creating a perception of weakness. Their vassals House Reyne of
            Castamere rebelled against Lord Tytos, and Tywin put down the rebellion personally,
            extinguishing their house and re-establishing the fearsome reputation of House Lannister.
            His ruthless destruction of House Reyne was immortalized in the song \"The Rains of Castamere\"
            and gave darker meaning to the common phrase \"A Lannister always pays his debts,\" which
            originally referred solely to the Lannister\'s vast fortune.\n\n</string>

    <!-- Array amb les descripcions curtes de la casa Lannister-->
    <string-array name="per_lann_descr">
        <item>Lord of Casterly Rock, 58 years.</item>
        <item>Lady of Casterly Rock, decreased.</item>
        <item>Lord Commander of the Kingsguard, 34 years. </item>
        <item>Dowager Queen, 34 years.</item>
        <item>Hand of the King , 27 years.</item>
    </string-array>


    <!-- Llista personatges de la casa Baratheon-->
    <string-array name="personatges_barat">
        <item>Robert Baratheon</item>
        <item>Cersei Lannister</item>
        <item>Joffrey Baratheon</item>
        <item>Myrceclla Baratheon</item>
        <item>Tommen Baratheon</item>
    </string-array>

    <string name="robert_name">Robert Baratheon</string>
    <string name="robert_desc">Lord of Storm\'s End , 36 years.</string>
    <string name="robert_desc_large">\"I\'m not trying to honor you. I\'m trying to get you to rum my kingdom while I eat, drink,
            and whore my way to an early grave.\"\n
            -Robert Baratheon to Eddard Stark\n\n
            Robert Baratheon was the ruler of the Seven Kingdoms, formally styled as Robert of the House
            Baratheon, the Firts of His Name, King of the Andals and the Firts Men, Lord of the Seven
            Kingdoms and Protector of the Realm. He tooks the throne through conquest in the war known
            as Robert\'s Rebellion. Robert was a great warrior in his youth. He killed Rhaegar Targaryen,
            Prince of Dragonstone, at the Battle of the Trident. After the war, Robert married Cersei
            Lannister to cement an alliance with House Lannister was loveless. Robert and Cersei have
            three children: Joffrey, Myrcella and Tommen. Unbeknnown to Robert, all three were actually
            fathered by Cersei\'s twin brother, Jaime Lannister.\n\n</string>

    <!-- Array amb les descripcions curtes de la casa Baratheon-->
    <string-array name="per_barat_descr">
        <item>Lord of Storm\'s End , 36 years.</item>
        <item>Dowager Queen, 34 years.</item>
        <item>King of the Andals and the First Men, 13 years. </item>
        <item>Princess, 10 years.</item>
        <item>King of the Andals and the First Men, 9 years.</item>
    </string-array>


    <!-- Llista personatges de la casa Tyrell-->
    <string-array name="personatges_tyr">
        <item>Mace Tyrell</item>
        <item>Alerie Hightower</item>
        <item>Willas Tyrell</item>
        <item>Garlan Tyrell</item>
        <item>Loras Tyrell</item>
        <item>Margaery Tyrell</item>
        <item>Olenna Redwyne</item>
        <item>Garth Tyrell</item>
    </string-array>

    <string name="mace_name">Mace Tyrell</string>
    <string name="mace_desc">Lord of Highgarden, 44 years.</string>
    <string name="mace_desc_large">
        \"Not now, Mace, Lord Tywin and I are speaking!\"\n
            -Lord Mace Tyrell is chided by his mother, Olenna\n\n

            Mace Tyrell is a recurring character in the fourth, fifth and sixth seasons. He is
            played by guest star Roger Ashton-Griffiths and debuts in \"The Lion and the Rose\".\n\n

            Lord Mace Tyrell is the Lord of Highgarden and head of House Tyrell. He is the father of
            Loras and Margaery Tyrell, and the son of Olenna Tyrell. He initially supported Renly
            Baratheon\'s claim to the Iron Throne in the War of the Five Kings, but after Renly\'s
            death he successfully negotiated an alliance with House Lannister to support King
            Joffrey\'s claim to the throne, on the condition that his daughter Margaery would marry
            Joffrey, making her the new queen and giving House Tyrell the prestige of entering into
            the royal bloodline. He has since been appointed both Master of Ships and Master of Coin
            on the Small Council.\n\n</string>

    <!-- Array amb les descripcions curtes de la casa Tyrell-->
    <string-array name="per_tyr_descr">
        <item>Lord of Highgarden, 44 years.</item>
        <item>Lady of Highgarden, 40 years.</item>
        <item>Cown of Highgarden, 27 years. </item>
        <item>Cown of Highgarden, 23 years.</item>
        <item>Lord Commander, 18 years.</item>
        <item>Queen Consorts, 17 years.</item>
        <item>Lady of Highgarden, 72 years</item>
        <item>Lord Senescal de Altojardín</item>
    </string-array>


    <!-- Llista personatges de la casa Greyjoy-->
    <string-array name="personatges_grey">
        <item>Balon Greyjoy</item>
        <item>Tara Greyjoy</item>
        <item>Theon Greyjoy</item>
        <item>Euron Greyjoy</item>
        <item>Victarion Greyjoy</item>
        <item>Aeron Greyjoy</item>
        <item>Alannys Harlaw</item>
    </string-array>

    <string name="balon_name">Balon Greyjoy</string>
    <string name="balon_desc">King of the Iron Islands and the North, alive.</string>
    <string name="balon_desc_large">
            \"No man gives me a crown. I pay the iron price. I will take my crown.\"\n
            -Balon Greyjoy\n\n

            King Balon Greyjoy is a recurring character in the second, third and sixth seasons. He
            is played by guest star Patrick Malahide and debuts in \"The Night Lands.\" Balon Greyjoy
            is the Lord Reaper of Pyke and the head of House Greyjoy. He is the father of Yara and
            Theon Greyjoy.\n\n

            Balon Greyjoy is the head of House Greyjoy and Lord of the Iron Islands. The Iron Islands
            are one of the constituent regions of the Seven Kingdoms and House Greyjoy is one of the
            Great Houses of the realm. House Greyjoy rule the region from their seat at Pyke and Balon
            also holds the title Lord Reaper of Pyke. He is a hard, ambitious and ruthless man.\n\n

            Balon is married to Alannys of House Harlaw. They had four children Rodrik, Maron, Yara
            and Theon. Yara is their only daughter.\n\n

            Eight years before the start of the series Balon declared himself King of the Iron Islands
            and rose in the rebellion against the Iron Throne to revive the \"Old Way\", which had once
            led the ironborn to rule much of the western coast of Westeros. He was, however, defeated
            in a bloody war. His elder two sons were killed and his third son, Theon, was taken by Lord
            Eddard Stark as a hostage for Balon\'s good behavior and obedience. Yara has remained on
            the Iron Islands and has become a warrior and captain in her own right, which is unusual
            for women on the isles.\n\n</string>

    <!-- Array amb les descripcions curtes de la casa Greyjoy-->
    <string-array name="per_grey_descr">
        <item>King of the Iron Islands and the North, alive.</item>
        <item>Princess, alive.</item>
        <item>Prince of Winterfell, 21 years. </item>
        <item>Captain of the Silence, alive.</item>
        <item>Lord Captain of the Iron Fleet, alive.</item>
        <item>Priest of the Drowned Gods, alive.</item>
        <item>Lady of Pyke, alive.</item>
    </string-array>


    <!-- Llista personatges de la casa Arryn-->
    <string-array name="personatges_arryn">
        <item>Jon Arryn</item>
        <item>Robert Arryn</item>
        <item>Harrold Hardyng</item>
    </string-array>

    <string name="jon_name">Jon Arryn</string>
    <string name="jon_desc">Warden of the East, 73 years.</string>
    <string name="jon_desc_large">
    \"The seed is strong.\"\n
    Jon Arryn\'s last words\n\n
    Jon Arryn was the Lord of the Eyrie and the head of House Arryn, one of the Great Houses
    of Westeros. Jos was the Warden of the East and Defender of the Vale. He was a respected
    nobleman were fostered by him during their adolescence. The Mad King condoned the kidnap
    of Eddard\'a sister and Robert\'s betrothed Lyanna Stark. The Mad King Eddard\'s father
    and brother killed for protesting against the kidnapping. When he then demanded that Eddard
    and Robert be turned over to the King\'s justice, Lord Arryn rebelled, calling his banners
    to war. House Stark and House Baratheon followed suit. The rebels forged an alliance with
    House Tully through marriage, with Eddard married Catelyn Tully and the then-elderly Jon
    to the young Lysa Tully.\n\n</string>

    <!-- Array amb les descripcions curtes de la casa Arryn-->
    <string-array name="per_arryn_descr">
        <item>Warden of the East, 73 years.</item>
        <item>Lord of the Eyrie, 8 years.</item>
        <item>Heir Eagles Nest, 18 years. </item>
    </string-array>


    <!-- Llista personatges de la casa Bolton-->
    <string-array name="personatges_bolt">
        <item>Roose Bolton</item>
        <item>Walda Bolton</item>
        <item>Ramsay Bolton</item>
    </string-array>

    <string name="roose_name">Roose Bolton</string>
    <string name="roose_desc">Lord of the Dreadfort, 45 years.</string>
    <string name="roose_desc_large">
    \"In my family we say, \'A naked man has few secrets, a flayed man, none.\'\"\n
    -Roose Bolton\n\n
    Roose Bolton is the head of House Bolton, a vassal family to House Stark of Winterfell.
    He is the Lord of the Dreadfort. Roose takes pride in his house sigil; the flayed man.
    Although torture is outlawed in the North, his family is famous for flaying the skin
    from their enemies as a means of torture and execution. Roose fought for Lord Eddard
    Stark in the civil war against House Targaryen known as Robert\'s Rebellion and proved
    his worth as a soldier in the Battle of the Trident. He advised Robert Baratheon to execute
    Ser Barristan Selmy, a legendary Kingsguard sworn to the Targaryens, but Robert overruled
    Roose and pardoned Selmy.\n\n
    Roose Bolton had a trueborn son, Domeric, who perished, forcing Roose to rely on his
    bastard son, Ramsay Snow.\n\n</string>


    <!-- Array amb les descripcions curtes de la casa Bolton-->
    <string-array name="per_bolt_descr">
        <item>Lord of the Dreadfort, 45 years.</item>
        <item>Lady of the Dreadfort, alive.</item>
        <item>Castellan of The Dreadfort, 23 years.</item>
    </string-array>
    <string name="title_activity_third">ThirdActivity</string>
</resources>
